You're listening to TIP. In today's episode, we're doing a bull and bear debate on CATL, the world's largest battery maker. My friend, Manus Karida, presents the bull case and Ralph Summerford, another dear friend of Varensen Accountant, who spent his time chasing financial shenanigans. Of course, place the bear. Now, chances are that you never heard of the company. Well, Ralph and I certainly hadn't either. We didn't even know it was pronounced cattle or CATL.
But if you've ever been in a Tesla or in a BMW, odds are that it ran under one of the batteries. Magnus walks us through how CTL came to control 4% of the global EV battery market and why any storage for AR data centers might be the growth engine the market has been priced in. Ralph digs into price deflation, an industry supplier flowed, and geopolitical risks that could hit with the stroke of a pen. You know, whenever we bullish on a stock,
We tend to surround ourselves with people who agree with us. You know, we like to sit in echo chambers. We like to all agree how smart we are because we all invest in the same thing. And if the thesis doesn't plan out, we can always come up with a reason why Mr. Margaret is just, you know, manic and, you know, doesn't see what we see. But of course, it's only a question before he realizes how wrong he is. Well, sometimes it happens and sometimes it doesn't happen. The point of trying to make is that we invited Ralph here to be the bear.
And not only today, but every quarter we're going to have an episode just like this where we're going to debate from a bull and a bear perspective. And I should also mention that both Ralph and Manus are members of our TIP mastermind community and we meet online and in person. Now, members are automatically invited to our live events like the intrinsic value conference in New York City here on September 19th and you can read more about how to attend in the show notes. But without further ado,
Let's jump right into the episode.
All opinions expressed by hosts and guests are solely their own and they may have investments in the securities discussed. Now for your host, Stig Brodersen. Welcome to the Investors Podcast. I'm your host, Stig Brodersen and today I'm here with my friends, Ralf and Manish. Pjens, how are you today? Doing great. Doing great, Stig. Thank you for having us. Yeah, glad to be here. Fantastic. And so Manish, you're presenting the bull case for
a huge company and perhaps it's a company that the audience doesn't even know about. And so I'm happy to say that in the first part of this episode, you will give us an overview of the business. And then we'll open the floor for perhaps a discussion among three of us about some related things. But anyways, I'm getting way ahead of myself. So let's just jump right into it, Manish. Please tell us about the company. Thanks, Steve. So this company that I would like to introduce today controls 40% market share.
in a growing industry. Most people probably have never seen their products. But if you have been in a Tesla or an electric BMW or Mercedes, there is more than a one-third chance that you have, you are on the vehicle that was running on one of their products. The company I'm talking about is CATL, contemporary Amperix technology limited, the largest battery maker in the world. And as of the most recent stock price,
Its market cap is about $280 billion, which means they are roughly the size of Shell. And my main thesis on CATL is that this company is more than a battery company. I think it is fast becoming the backbone of the energy infrastructure. It powers EVs, it stores renewable power, and now increasingly it's becoming the core power infrastructure player in the AI data centers.
You know, Manish, I have to admit when I first discussed this company with you when we talked about it, I'd never heard of CATL. I wasn't even sure if you pronounced it cattle or CATL. What's the founding story about this company? Yeah, it's not a well-known company in the western world, but the company has a very interesting backstory.
So CATL was founded by Robin Zeng, who is the CEO of the company. It was started in 2011, but the roots of the company date back to much earlier. So in the 1990s, Robin Zeng was working as a technical director at a company called SAE Magnetics, which was a subsidiary of the Japanese conglomerate TDK that used to make electronic components such as computer hard drives, disks, etc.
So Robin Zeng saw firsthand the consumer electronics boom that was taking shape in the late 90s and the opportunity for the lithium batteries in those products. So he took his first big bet. He decided to quit TDK and along with two other colleagues, he founded a lithium battery company called Amperix Technology Limited or ATL. So that's CATL without the C.
So he founded ATL and at that point they did not have a battery technology of their own and instead they licensed a technology patent from Bell Labs. But that technology had a fatal flaw as the batteries would swell up after repeated charging and Robin Zheng being a deeply technical engineer along with his team somehow managed to solve this issue and turned this defective license into a product.
that landed them some big customers. And the key one being Apple in 2003, when the company started manufacturing batteries for the Apple iPod. So that win cemented Robin Zang's credibility and established ATL as a benchmark in the mobile battery world. Now the success of ATL caught the eye of TDK, the former employer of Robin Zang.
and TDK decided to acquire ATL for about $100 million and also asked Robin Zhang to stay on and run the company as a TDK subsidiary. So it was like a full circle for Robin Zhang. He left TDK to build something of his own and he was now back with them. But now with a large Japanese parent behind them, ATL was scaling its manufacturing and scale their Apple relationship.
and started making batteries for the iPhone. And ATL ultimately grew into the world's largest smartphone battery maker. And what is interesting about Robin Zeng is that he didn't stop at that. After dominating the smartphone battery market, he started to set his sight on the next big wave in batteries, which was batteries for electric vehicles. Robin Zeng could see that China was making electric vehicles as a strategic industry.
and was providing state support to homegrown companies. But this is where there was a problem. Because ATL was owned by TDK, which was a Japanese company. He knew that a foreign-controlled ATL would not get the same support from the government as a domestic company would. So what does Robin Zheng do? He takes another big bet. He gathers a group of Chinese investors led by himself and his deputy.
and spun off ATL's EV Battery Division into a brand new Chinese controlled company called CATL. Robin Zhang and his co-investors took 85% equity in the company and TDK kept the remaining 15%. And that's how CATL came into existence. Well, incredible. And thank you, Manish. You know, you could say so far, so good.
But then we are having this relatively small company, they're making smartphone batteries, but then all of a sudden in barely a decade, they're powering 4% of the world's EVs. Like how does something like that happen? Yeah, so CATL has developed some key competencies which have led to this massive growth, such as their strong focus on R&D, their vertical integration and the manufacturing scale advantage. And we can talk about these drivers in more detail later.
But I believe there is one important factor which I think has been a key driver behind the rise of CATL. And that is their relationships with key customers during their growth phase. And two of them really stand out. The first one was with the German automaker BMW. So back in 2012, BMW wanted to build an electric vehicle and wasn't happy with any of the batteries on the market. They first approached BYD.
and BYD declined to provide batteries to external customers. So BMW took a gamble and gave this relatively unknown EV battery company, CATL, a critical contract to be their battery supplier in China. And it wasn't a purchase order for BMW from BMW. They basically embedded their engineers inside CATL's facilities to co-design the battery for their EV.
And I think that education in German engineering and a stamp of approval from a global automaker is what put CATL on the map. So that was their first key relationship that gave them an initial recognition that they can make high performance batteries for a demanding customer. And if PMW gave CATL the credibility, it was Tesla that gave them the global stage. Just a quick backstory. So when CATL was formed in 2011,
There was another EV revolution happening in the US. Tesla had gone public and they had signed Panasonic to be their battery suppliers for their model S cars. CETL did not enter Tesla's supply chain roughly a decade later around 2020 when Tesla entered China and started sourcing batteries from CETL. And that's when the growth of CETL went vertical. So just to give you some numbers, so in 2020 CETL's revenue was
roughly about $7 billion and in 2025, just five years later, their revenue jumped by more than eight times to more than $60 billion. And it's not just the growth in revenue. The scale of CATL's battery production today is hard to picture. The company is on track to deliver close to a thousand gigawatt hours of battery in 2026. And to just put that in perspective, that's enough electricity storage to power all of Singapore.
or the city of New York for about a week. Today, Robin Zang is sometimes called the invisible king of the global battery supply chain. He's still owns about 22% of the company and the founding team holds over 35%. So this is a founder led, founder controlled, deeply technical R&D focused company with skin in the game. And I believe with a very long time horizon. Wow, Manish, if I could have one thing there,
We, as values investors, always are looking for a company led by a founder who has more than a minor stake. In other words, they have skin in the game. And it's clear that Zing has a personal stake in the game. And I hear that I read that the estimates is greater than $53 billion is his personal stake. And another point about Zing,
He leads a culture of giving back to his community. He grew up very poor. He was from a very small city in China and the manufacturing facilities of CATL are in a city of about 400,000 but it's located very close to its hometown. He's expressed his desire to give back and reward loyalty and those are great attributes of a leader that we're always looking for. So,
What's the competitive advantage, Manish, that allows them to have such a high market share? Why are competitors catching up with them? Yeah, I'm like, well, CATL has been number one in EV battery market share for nine straight years. Its nearest rival is BYD at around 16% market share. Now, most listeners would know BYD. It was Buxia's famous investment in China.
led by Charlie Munger back in 2008. And that investment returned roughly 20 times before Berkshire fully exited last year. Today, BYD is the largest EV maker in the world and it's vertically integrated, meaning they make their own batteries. They do sell some batteries to others, but the vast majority is consumed by their own cars. So in a way they are a competitor to CATL and in a sense they are not.
where PYD and CATL do compete with each other is in the R&D space. Both companies want to be seen as the leading edge of battery technology. For example, this year in March, PYD came out with a battery that charges from 10% to 97% in about nine minutes. And a month later, CATL came out with a competing product that goes from 10% to 98% in under seven minutes.
In this R&D competition between CATL and BYD, the Chinese lead over everyone keeps widening. And the third largest player in this sector is the Korean LG Energy Solutions. They have roughly about 9% market share. So this isn't a close race. CATL is about 2.5 times larger than the nearest rival.
You know, I always feel a bit torn about whenever I'm looking these mageshias up because I think it very much also depends on Who's the protagonist in the story right sometimes you would be looking at someone who has very low mageshia and you're saying Wow look at all this growth they have ahead because yo that's not a small mageshia And then of course you also have the other side of the spectrum where you have someone like Chtl it has 40% you're saying wow look like they have they're the compass like they have to lead because they have all this mageshia whereas others would say they have
They have so much to lose, I guess. But what allows them to have such a strong lead in terms of mileage and why aren't competitors catching up? Yeah, so I would say there are probably three main reasons for that. I would say the first one would be scale economics. So if you look at CATL, you see a checklist like they are the cheapest producer, they have the biggest R&D budget, the best technology, and you might assume that the MOT is one of those.
But I think the more is that these advantages feed each other and create a flywheel. Being the biggest makes them the cheapest. Being the cheapest makes them the most profitable. That profit funds a large R&D budget, which helps them build the best technology and win more customers, which makes them bigger still. And with the scale CTL has
They have been pushing upstream into mining with stakes in the mining companies. So they control the raw materials and they have gone downstream by designing their cells straight into the car platforms. So for a competitor, it isn't about trying to catch up on one thing. They are chasing a flywheel that just keeps spinning faster every year. I believe the second advantage they have is the customer switching cost. Now, you might think that how can batteries have high switching cost?
Well, once a battery is engineered into a car platform, it's designed years ahead of production and has to pass through a variety of safety, crash and durability testing before a single car gets shipped. So design win isn't a one year order. It's logged in for the entire life of that platform, which is typical about five to eight years. And that creates a sticky predictable revenue. And CATL has the broadest set of customers in the industry.
Tesla, BMW, Mercedes, Volkswagen, and nearly every Chinese eb maker except dyD. So the switching cost creates another advantage. And the last one that I will talk about is the product complexity, especially in the energy storage space. So a grid scale storage system looks like a giant block of battery, but a single gigawatt hour installation can contain on the order of several million individual components.
And in one of the interviews, Robin's saying pension that it contains more components than a Boeing 747. These storage systems are built to last more than 20 years. So the reliability bar is very high. And that makes them hard to manufacture at scale. So I would say that scale, economics, switching costs and product complexity are the three main sources of competitive advantage for them. Let's take a quick break and hear from today's sponsors.
One part of being an investor that I don't think gets enough attention is how hard it can be to continue to improve as an investment researcher. And for myself, I often find that when I finish a great conversation with some industry expert or fund manager, my head is full of ideas. But by the time I sit down to write it all up, half of them are already gone. That's why I've been using Plod Note Pro.
It's a small device that sticks to the back of my phone and captures the conversation and hands me back a clean, searchable recap. And so the key points, the follow-ups, the things I usually want to act on, it has all of that. And that allows me to stay present in the room and set a scribbling notes that I won't be able to read back later. And I notoriously have very bad handwriting. And so it's changed how I prep and how I follow up with investors. It's also built for people who take conversation seriously. Enterprise grade security.
So if you're recording calls with clients or industry contacts, that's covered too. So if you live in meetings, calls and interviews, we'll give it a look. Go to plod.ai slash WSB and use code WSB for 10% off. That's plod.ai slash WSB code WSB and always get consent before you record a conversation. Curious about online trading but haven't taken the first step yet?
You're not alone. And plus 500 futures is a great place to start. The futures markets are moving fast. And with plus 500, you can explore popular assets like oil, gold, S&P 500, Bitcoin and more. From crypto to commodities, there's always something happening. The platform is super easy to use so you can trade on the go right from your phone. You can get started with just $100 and jump into the action. See something interesting? Once your account is open, you can trade it in just a couple of clicks.
And if you're not quite ready yet, you can practice with a free demo account. No risk, no pressure. With 20 years of experience, plus 500 makes trading more accessible than ever. Check it out at plus500.com. Trading and futures involves risks of loss and is not suitable for everyone. Not all applicants will qualify. Plus 500. It's trading with a plus. They say every day your business is late to AI. You fall two days behind in the competition.
They're only moving faster. Fortunately, there's NetSuite Next. You probably already know NetSuite, the AI-powered business suite that securely connects all your data, financials, inventory, commerce, HR, and CRM all in one source of truth. Trusted by over 43,000 customers. NetSuite Next is the next huge leap because now AI is built into everything you do. It surfaces custom insights throughout your day. AI agents work alongside you on the routine stuff.
And anytime you've got a question about anything, you just ask like you're talking to a colleague and I use it. And really, I think you should too. For the first time ever, you can try NetSuite next for free. If your revenue is at least in the seven figures, go to net suite dot AI slash TIP built for every industry ready for every boardroom net suite dot AI slash TIP. All right. Back to the show. So Manish, CETL being the largest battery maker.
I'm almost inclined to say that the market or at least institutional investors must understand this competitive advantage or at least so we like to think but we also say that institutional investors are the ones swinging the market and yet you see these crazy fluctuations of what 80% on average for the largest companies. So perhaps they do and perhaps they don't but in any case the angle we are looking for are what are the drivers that overall the market has not fully appreciated.
So why is the market not pricing right now in your opinion? Yeah, so the competitive advantage that we have discussed are pretty well understood by the market. But what I think is underappreciated are two new growth engines that are still in the early stage of their life cycle. And I believe the market hasn't fully underwritten them. The first one is the power infrastructure for the AI data center. So AI data center
cross enormous spiky workloads that the power grid cannot smoothly deliver. So if you picture an AI data center, you have tens of thousands of GPUs all computing in parallel. And then they pause for a split second to synchronize. And then they fire another compute cycle. This massive parallel cycle creates spikes in the power demand, sometimes swinging hundreds of megawatts in seconds.
But the legacy power grids are not designed to ramp up and down fast enough to follow these compute spikes. That's the gap that CATL batteries fill in. They sit in between the spiky compute loads and the steady power grid. They absorb these surges in power in between. And as the total power demand continues to climb at these data centers, the appetite for this kind of storage buffering grows with it.
Manishi, I have done quite a bit of research on data centers lately and hopefully that's one of the topics that we'll cover in the future podcasts to put a little bit of insight into what a data center storage means to CATL. The data center industry estimates that by 2030, just a little over three years from now, that data centers will require twice as much power. That is, they will need 200 gigawatts
of continuous power. And to put those continuous power watts into perspective, think about this. One gigawatt, one gigawatt of continuous power is required for the city of Seattle, Washington or San Francisco, California. 10 gigawatts of continuous power is required for the city of New York or the city of Los Angeles.
200 gigawatts, that is 200 gigawatts of continuous power is required for the state of California. All that additional power from the data centers requires storage to furnish that clean, steady power that you talked about. That is truly mind-boggling when you think about this. Yeah, I would say it's quite mind-boggling for sure.
CATL is already the world's number one energy storage supplier. And I think the two things make it even more attractive play. First is that the storage segment carries higher margins for CATL than the core EV battery business because of the complexity and the durability requirements that we talked about. And the second point, which I find more interesting is that CATL isn't just selling batteries to these data centers.
It is now systematically assembling a full-stack energy ecosystem for the storage through power distribution inside the data center. They are even buying into the power equipment makers and servicing the entire energy stack. This I think has the potential to transform CATL from just an energy storage supplier to a strategic infrastructure partner for the entire AI compute build out.
And the second potential growth engine, which I think is still in the early stage that can have a huge upside for the company is the licensing model called LRS, which stands for License, Royalty and Service. So CATL is effectively locked out of owning a factory in the US for geopolitical reasons. So rather than fight it out, they have found a workaround where they get into a licensing deal with an American company.
And it's the American partner that builds, owns and runs the manufacturing plant while CATL just provides the license of its technology and collects a royalty fee. So CATL and Ford recently did this licensing deal for the Ford's Michigan Battery Plant. And in that Ford owns the plant, land, equipment and highest the workforce. CATL has no equity and only offers battery chemistry and technology.
and gets a royalty fee in return. CATL hasn't disclosed the economics of the licensing fee, but if it is in the three to four percent range that these deals are typically done at, then that's a very high margin capital light income. And that framework can extend beyond EV batteries to even data storage for the AI data storage compute that we talked about.
Well, you're exactly right and the royalty and licensing fees can be a gold mine. If anyone has watched the TV show Shark Tank, Kevin Allure, who's also known as Mr. Wonderful, one of the venture capitalists, he frequently offers to invest, but not for an equity state. He's looking for a royalty or a licensing fee. And there's a big reason for that as you pointed out. It can be a huge return.
on the investment without the big investment in brick and mortar. Yeah, so the important point here that I want to do highlight is that this is still in the early phase. The model is under scrutiny by the US lawmakers. So CATL obviously feels that this is a win-win solution for both parties. But the geopolitics has many dimensions and it's not yet a short short win. But if CATL can scale this LRS framework in the US,
the high margin royalty revenue can provide a big boost to the stock price. Manish, I'm going to stop interrupting you, except to say that the scrutiny by the US lawmakers is a big, big but. And I'll talk more about this later. For now, less suffice it to say that a licensing deal of 3% to 4% of revenue would be wonderful, but it could easily get wiped out.
by the simple stroke of a pen. Well said, Ralph. So with that in mind, let's dive into the financials. Now, let's talk about some of the risks that we might see in the numbers, like just here at the very top, as we're looking at the income statement, I see the revenue was flat from 2023 to 2025. How did that happen? Yeah, so let's get into the pun stuff. So starting with the revenue being flat from 2023 to 2025 that you mentioned, Stig.
So the biggest cost for CATL is the raw materials that go into the battery, which currently is mostly lithium. And lithium prices became dramatically cheaper over the last couple of years. And CATL passed those savings on as lower prices to its customers. So the company sold far more battery volume, made more profits, but the headline revenue barely moved.
And the second point that I want to highlight in the financials is that there is a big mismatch between their net income and the operating cash flows. So last year, CATL earned about $11 billion in profit, but it generated close to about $20 billion in operating cash flows. So that's nearly double. This high operating cash flow allows the company to spend on CAPEX, margin acquisitions, return cash to shareholders through dividends and buybacks.
and the company still managed to have higher cash balance on their balance sheet after all of that. The reason why operating cash flow is so much higher than the profit is because CATL has a large negative working capital, meaning that it sells through its inventory and collects money from customers months before it has to pay to its suppliers. So in effect, its suppliers are its largest lenders, funding the growth for CATL almost interest-free.
And this is similar to Amazon's playbook. They get paid on e-commerce sales today and pay the suppliers much later and let that float on the flywheel. But this is where the risk also resides. There is a limit to how much you can stretch your payables. And the Chinese authorities are asking large firms to start paying the SME suppliers sooner. So for CETL, that likely means that part of their interest free float
might unwind and a period of readjustment in how it funds its growth. I don't think it will break the model because much of CATL's payables are to large suppliers which are outside the SME rules that the authorities are pushing for. But I would say it's still a real headwind to watch out for.
Yeah, Manish, and there's a big debate around China's state involvement in domestic champions and how subsidies have helped companies like CATL and BYD. Does CATL have any government golden share or would it succeed without state support? Yeah, so let me just talk about golden share a bit. So golden share in China is basically like a special management share.
typically given to the state or a government fund. And the main purpose is for the state to have some kind of regulatory oversight on the company. It does not impact the day-to-day operations of the company, but the state gets some veto powers and is mostly used for companies in the social media space where you want to have some control on what content gets distributed to the general population. So talking about CATL, CATL is a founder controlled company with
no publicly disclosed golden share. And yet, like virtually every strategic Chinese manufacturer, it did benefit from state support early on. The biggest support that CATLC was the restriction that functionally locked out foreign competition from the China support program and gave CATLC a captive domestic market to scale up.
It wasn't until Elon Musk negotiated Tesla's entry in China in 2019 that the state scrapped the restriction and allowed foreign competition to come back in. And I believe the second support that Seattle received was when it came in the form of these consumer purchase subsidies that helped create the EV demand in China. So these subsidies are also now fully phased out at the end of 2022.
But what is worth mentioning here is that to the mindset which is at the top of the company. So the peak of the subsidy boom in 2017, Robin Zheng sent his staff a famous letter in Chinese which roughly translates to if you stand where the wind blows, even a pig can fly. His point being that a strong subsidy tailwind in the captive home market can make even a mediocre company look great.
And his message was a warning to his team against the dependency on a subsidy and to build a cost and technology advantage that could help them win globally without the state support. And that warning got tested for real. So China removed the state, the restrictions of foreign competition. And the competition came running back in. LG Panasonic, they all came back in.
So basically the wind stopped and CATL still holds a leading global share in the EV battery market and they earn margins which are above the best of the industry. So the point here is that Robin Zeng didn't confuse a policy support with a durable advantage. He instead used the government support as a temporary support to internally build a system that now gives them a long-term competitive advantage. Now,
for the other side of the story because no thesis survives without the bear case. But on the risk that we talked about though, are there any more worth putting on the table before I get in there? Yeah, absolutely. So I think the first one, which I think is the biggest for CATL is the geopolitical risk. So CATL is effectively world out of the US market, which is the second largest market.
for EV batteries. The company is on the Pentagon's list of companies that work for the Chinese military. This is something that the company has contested hard. Robin Zeng has sent executives to Washington to make the case, but so far without success. So CATL's counter to this restriction is the licensing model that I talked about.
And as an example, that the Ford partnership in Michigan where CATL licenses its technology rather than owning a manufacturing facility and in return collects a fees on that license. I think it's a clever way to circumvent the restriction and it's a template that CATL could repeat with other partners. But having said that, as I mentioned, it's still in the early stage and it's not a done deal yet.
So the risk is still very real and something investors need to watch out for. Let's go deeper, Manish, on the licensed royalty and service. I think you called it the LRIS model. LRIS is often spun as an asset like growth. In reality, it may be better spun as a defensive capitulation. By surrendering direct ownership and customer relations to Ford and GM, CATL is admitting
that direct Chinese ownership is politically toxic under the US Inflation Reduction Act, accepting a mere 3 to 4% royalty fee turns that invisible king you mentioned into a low-rent IP landlord. This model makes CTL what I, CATL what I would call a ghost in the machine vulnerable to a stroke of the pen where the US regulators can sever the IP link at any time.
and leave CATL with zero physical assets to reclaim. Not only a stroke of the pen loss by handing over the blueprint for high density packs to 4DGM, not only are you handing over the blueprint, CATL is training the very competitors who seek to exclude it. Let's call it LRS leakage. You're right. It's a threat that is very real.
Yeah, I totally agree. As the LRS framework evolves, this will be an important aspect to watch out for. I mean, after all, CATL itself learned the manufacturing skills from other players, such as BMW. So it's definitely possible for US manufacturers to learn from CATL. Although, with the high R&D focus that CATL has, they are constantly moving up the technology curve. But then training competition can still be a threat to watch out for.
I would say that second risk that I want to put on the table is the price war at home. So China's battery and EV sector has seen a brutal, brutal price war. So much so that Robin Zhang himself has publicly asked the industry to stop computing purely on price. The counter here is that the growth in the energy storage segment, especially the AI data center demand that we discussed, it is
a new higher margin faster growing segment where CATL is number one and the company is moving into a full stack power storage solution where the competition is less intense. Again, storage is not immune to price pressure and its per unit prices are falling too but it's a higher margin than the EV batteries business and it's still in the early stage of the growth curve. And the third risk that I would talk about is the
technology disruption risk. Now, battery technology is improving at a very high rate. As a rough rule, every two years, the energy density in the battery packs climbs by about 20%. And to add to that, there is faster charging, longer battery life, better cold weather performance, and the innovation spans battery chemistry, materials, cell designs, et cetera.
So the danger here is that the new chemistry such as the solid state or the sodium ion batteries or something else, leapfrogs the existing LFP and the NMC batteries that CATL is dominant today. And the counter here is that CATL spends more on R&D than anyone in the industry. The company isn't relying on any single chemistry. It is already developing and scaling sodium ion batteries in parallel.
So, the bet here is that whatever the next innovation is, CATL is likely working on it too. So, the risk is real, but my view is that the disruptor and the incumbent may just turn out to be the same company here. My nation, I agree. Before we talk about valuation, let me jump in and amplify some of those risks and present a little bit more on the bearer case for CATL.
The Volcker celebrates volume growth as a sign of dominance, but a forensic look at the numbers reveals a treadmill effect. Recall I'm a forensic accountant in that pun I intended to make. In a recent fiscal period, CATL reported a 21.8% growth and shipped gigawatt-hour volume, yet the top-line revenue contracted by 9.7%.
This price deflation acted as a massive 130% drag on growth. This happened because CATL's long-term agreements utilize raw material indexation. The company is contractually obligated to pass manufacturing efficiency gains and commodity savings directly to their OEMs. CATL is running exponentially faster
to stay in the same place. Financially, so it's surrendering its pricing power to maintain utilization. Also, the recent 15.5% profit margin expansion achieved while the revenue was shrinking is a mathematically temporary windfall. It's not a new baseline. It doesn't indicate technological superiority. Rather, call it a cost wedge profitability fluke.
What an investor will likely see is that 15.5% net profit will regress to a tighter 11% to 12% historical bands. Last year, CATL reported almost two times as much cash flow as profit. This two times delta exists because CATL uses its dominant position to squeeze suppliers by a higher day's payable outstanding.
Essentially, it's an interest-free loan from its supply chain, like you said, at Amazon. However, the Chinese authorities have already now demanding and mandated that large firms pay SMEs faster. As this interest-free loan is called in, CATL's funding model plays a painful readjustment, stripping away the cash used for buybacks and dividends. The interest-free floats, like that enjoyed by Buffett.
than other insurance companies will go away. Although, yours truly believes that the energy storage system is a cyclical buffer to slowing EV sales. The ESS, the energy storage systems, is sensitive to utility capital budgets, to global interest rates, and to AI spend. This ESS buffer can be viewed as a high beta on the global micro environment.
CATL's uncontested expansion may slow. Being the largest, they're the biggest target for all the competitors. They may be the slowest mover towards solid state disruption, and they have the most to lose from the next generation chemistry, unless of course they invent it. With subsidies from the Chinese government gone, recall the pig in the wind, CATL faces a gravitational pull not seen since 2011.
Some of those gravitational pulls include, one, a utilization risk. With new plants in Hungary and Germany, CATL has a massive fixed overhead. Any minor slowdown in European EV adoption due to subsidy cliffs will leave this capacity unabsorbed, turning growth assets into margin angst. Commodity concentration
Despite the vertical integration, CATO remains a shadow commodity trading house. Its stock price may be viewed by bears as a proxy for lithium and nickel volatility, not a reflection of R&D prowess. The European Protectionist's wall, the EU carbon border adjustment mechanism, CBAM, acts as a targeted tax on Chinese cells.
And a key founder, key man, risk. CATL is inextricably tied to Robert Zing's personal standing. With a 22 and a half percent ownership, deep ties to Beijing, any shift in his political standing represents an existential, unheachable risk for shareholders. And I will remind folks about Alibaba.
Thanks, Ralph. These are valid risk. I'll get off my soapbox now. Go ahead. Yeah, I agree. I think these are valid risk, especially the geopolitical risk linked to European protection. And anybody investing in China has to be comfortable with taking on the geopolitical risk. That's something which is always there. For the other ones, let me try to kind of address them one by one.
So the first one is the utilization risk linked to the fixed overheads at these overseas plants in Hungary and Germany. So it is true that a slowdown in the European EV industry will have some impact on CATL. But I would also say that being the lowest cost producer, CATL might be better placed in managing the downturn compared to the competition. I mean, we have seen subsidies
getting removed in China resulting in overall EV slowdown. But the dominance of CATL in China has continued. Now with regards to your point about commodity price volatility linked to the lithium prices basically. So the company is actively developing new battery chemistries such as the sodium ion batteries as a response to this very risk. So sodium as opposed to lithium is widely available.
The issue currently with sodium and batteries today is that the energy density is lower compared to the lithium based batteries. But again, as that technology improves, this could be a good hedge for CATL against the commodity price volatility. And finally, on a point about key man risk, well, that again is a very real risk. Robin Zeng has been the key driver behind the company and is the largest shareholder. I am less worried about
a shift in the political standing because first of all, CATL operates in a sector that China wants to grow. So they have a strong mutual alignment on that. And secondly, you know, Roman Zhang maintains a low profile and really speaks in public. So the chances of him rubbing the regulators or the state authorities the wrong way is quite low. But again, it's a valid risk and something I would categorize as
low probability, but with potentially high impact and very difficult to hedge. Let's take a quick break and hear from today's sponsors.
The platform is super easy to use so you can trade on the go right from your phone. You can get started with just $100 and jump into the action. See something interesting? Once your account is open, you can trade it in just a couple of clicks. And if you're not quite ready yet, you can practice with a free demo account. No risk, no pressure. With 20 years of experience plus 500 makes trading more accessible than ever. Check it out at plus500.com. Trading and futures involves risks of loss and is not suitable for everyone.
Not all applicants will qualify, plus 500. It's trading with a plus.
Most leaders are automating work. They've never actually watched happen. They know how the process is supposed to go. Someone walked them through it once. It sounded clean. But the version that runs day to day looks completely different. And nobody's doing anything wrong. That gap is bigger than most of us realize. And it means the decisions about what to fix, automate or hand to AI are running on gut, not data. That's exactly the problem that today's sponsor, Scribe, was built to fix. Scribe is a workflow AI platform trusted by
94% of the Fortune 500 and Scribe Optimize is your AI roadmap. It passively captures how your team actually works across your approved business apps, no interviews, no manual process mapping, and follows workflows wherever they go, even when they start in one tool and finish in another. The dashboard shows you what's happening and where the time is going live right now, not a report someone built last quarter.
And its top issues view doesn't just flag your biggest inefficiencies, it tells you why they're happening and gives AI powered recommendations with estimated time savings built in. Importantly, it's a leadership visibility tool, not employee monitoring. It only runs on apps your admin approves user level data is anonymized by default and sensitive information is automatically redacted and never leaves your firewall.
To see Optimize in Action, head to scribe.how.wsb and mention the investor's podcast for a 30-day risk-free trial. That's S-C-R-I-B-E.how.wsb. They say every day your business is late to AI, you fall two days behind in the competition, they're only moving faster. Fortunately, there's NetSuite next. You probably already know NetSuite, the AI-powered business suite that securely connects all your data
financials, inventory, commerce, HR and CRM all in one source of truth trusted by over 43,000 customers. NetSuite next is the next huge leap because now AI is built into everything you do. It surfaces custom insights throughout your day. AI agents work alongside you on the routine stuff. And anytime you've got a question about anything, you just ask like you're talking to a colleague and I use it and really I think you should too.
For the first time ever, you can try NetSuite next for free. If your revenues at least in the seven figures go to net suite dot a i slash t i p built for every industry ready for every boardroom net suite dot a i slash t i p. All right, back to the show. Now, let's get to the fun stuff. I think you already said, man, is that we were getting to the fun stuff, but I wanted to talk about the valuation. So with all of this kept in mind.
How do you think about the current valuation and is it a buy right now? Okay, so as of today, the current stock price for shares trading in Chenjin, CATL's market cap is around $280 billion and with a cash sitting on the balance sheet, the enterprise value, which is what you actually pay for the operating business is close to $250 billion.
Now against a $14 billion of operating profit over the last four quarters, that's about 18 times multiple EB2 a bit. And if you look at the P multiple, that's roughly trading at about 21 times, which I think for a global leader like CATL is neither demanding nor cheap. The company has a high return on invested capital of around 17% and a return on equity of about 25%.
So there is a good enough chance that the operating business roughly doubles in value over the next five years. And if the multiples remain where they are, you can expect about 15% annual return before you add a dividend yield of another point or two. So to summarize, it's a dominant cash-generative, fondle-led business with high returns on capital that can potentially double the value of the business in
five years. There are obviously both upside and downside cases. We discuss about the growth engines around AI data centers and the licensing model. If they surprise on the upside, then the returns can be even more meaningful. And the downside case is that the domestic price war intensifies and the LRS model doesn't scale in the US due to geopolitical tension. Most little listeners
are probably based outside of China. So how can a non-Chinese investor buy the stock, Manish? Isn't it listed in two places? Yeah, that's correct, Ralph. So CATLA is dual listed. The A shares are traded in China with the ticker 300750 and the H shares are traded in Hong Kong with the ticker 37050. So same company, same one share, one vote.
same dividend per share. But if you look at the stock price and after adjusting for the FX rate, you will notice that the Hong Kong shares trade at a big premium of roughly 30 to 35% to the mainland China shares. And that's actually opposite to the norm. Normally for a dual listed Chinese company is the mainland A shares that trade at a premium.
because Chinese domestic investors face capital controls and they cannot freely buy in Hong Kong. So their demand gets concentrated into the local listing. But for CATL it's the opposite case. And the reason is pure supply and demand. So the Hong Kong float is relatively small and the demand from global investors is quite high. The Hong Kong and Chinese shares are not fungible.
meaning that you can't buy in one market and freely convert and sell it in the other market. It's a bit like TSMC whose US listed shares have long traded at a premium to the domestic Taiwan shares. So if an international investor, if you have access to the Chinese shares, then that is a cheaper way to get access to this business. Some brokers provide access to domestic Chinese listings using something called the Northbound Stock Connect.
But this is usually limited to the institutional investors. For smaller retail investors, Hong Kong shares are the only option. These are freely accessible to everyone, but you will have to pay a premium to own them. Now, CATL has been widening the Hong Kong float. So after the Hong Kong IPO in 2025, they did a follow on placement in 2026. And yet the global demand
for so high that the premium hasn't compressed much. My personal view is that in the long run, Hong Kong shares should trade at a premium of about 10 to 20% range using TSMC as the reference. So TSMC has average at around 15% premium. But how and when that gap will compress is hard to say.
Yeah, we've covered a lot about CATL here. If you had to boil it down and distill it to a single bottom line for investor looking at a stock right now in mid 2026, what's the takeaway? A listeners' takeaway is that CATL is not just an EV battery play. It has the potential to become the backbone of the future energy infrastructure and increasingly for the AI data centers.
It is not without risks. You have to be comfortable with the geopolitical friction. And if the AI storage growth continues and the LRIS licensing model proves scalable, then there is a very real compelling story for this business. So without taking any sides, I don't want to get here too much mellow between a bull and a bear. I have to say still, reading up on CETL, I was more excited about batteries.
They were not for vehicles, but really for stabilizing power grids and AI data centers. And in my past, actually in my very first job rather college, I was working with power grids, which I never thought would come in handy ever. But here we are 12 years into running the MS podcast. And apparently now it makes sense that there was my first job. And I was just I'm amazed by how many technological changes you've seen within power grids. And I know like for most people, they're probably I don't know.
turning the light on and off or whatever. But like, but someone was sort of like looking at the nerdy inside of power grids. Like, it's almost like the laws of physics have changed over the past 15 years. And even before everyone talked about AI, you had these sophisticated tools that could pretty well predict demand supply. And you need that to stabilize the grid. So, you know, one reason why you call a nuclear
had been used or are still being used for electricity generation is because they had such a low marginal cost, but also because they refer to what is base load. So, you know, we use electricity all the time. And so it's very predictable and which is very useful. And you can you will always have someone so much that you need. Of course, you have different times during the day when you need more electricity. For example, you know, generally more during the day than during the night.
But then you also, like even during the day, you have, you know, whenever you wake up before you go to work, and then, you know, that then there's a peak period. And, you know, then you come back from work and you fire up the TV and you cook dinner or whatever. And so, like, you can predict that pretty comfortably what's going to happen. So you can more or less see that demand of electricity on a curb. And then you have supply. And as the world has started to rely more on renewables,
that energy has become somewhat more intermittent because you're looking at something like solar. You don't always know clouds in the sky, how much or the wind blowing for that matter. And then to the ladder, if you're thinking about something as simple as wind, you're thinking, well, you just need to blow and the more blows, the more electricity you generate. That is directional correct. But you also have something called cutout speed. It's roughly 90 kilometers an hour and above that.
The turbine pitches with the blade, it just stops. I think that's probably the easiest way to think about it. So it's not like a linear curve, I guess that's what I'm trying to say. But of course, from a purely physical perspective, you have bigger issues than just predicting demand to supply. And for the longest time with renewables, the issue has been that you can't store the energy. Because from the moment the wind hits the turbine's blade, electricity has to be used the moment that it's being made.
you can think about it as it's a pipe and not a bucket. And then there's another dimension and sorry for geeking so much out here, but like the longer it has to travel, the more transmissions it has to go through. Then it also uses some of that power. Anyways, I get to carry away here. But of course, with today's battery technology, much of that is changing and it will continue to change in favor of better storage.
So you're looking at a company like CETL that would benefit from the underlying tailwind. No pun intended. Even if you look beyond the AI data centers. But of course the data centers accelerate the need for batteries. And if you're looking at electricity, you also have several issues. The most important, the one that we're probably most aware of as consumers is grid stability. And so you need the right frequency.
Perhaps you heard that the frequency we use in Europe is 50 Hertz. It's 60 Hertz in the US. And it's for purely historical reasons that you have different frequencies. The story is that in the 1890s, the German company AG, they picked 50 Hertz because it fits the metric system better. And then in American Westinghouse, they went with 60 Hertz, part because they literally observed that the lights flickered less at 60 Hertz. So that became the standard.
And for someone who traveled around Japan a bit, I can't help but mention that in Japan, the order German equipment in Tokyo, but then in Osaka and the southern part, the order American. So actually to this very day, Japan runs in two different frequencies. You know, in the northern part, it's one in the southern, it's another. And it's purged by accident. It started 130 years ago and it's still going on today.
So you can't share that power unless it runs through really, really expensive converters and it's actually quite complicated. And of course, you don't have the same issue between Europe and the US because they have their own power grids. And even like within those regions, you actually have a ton of smaller power grids and it all patched together. It's actually kind of freakish whenever you really get to study how the power grids work. But I'm telling this story because I find it to be like a microcosm of how much randomness we're facing.
But it's something we still have to act on today. And it's important because every power plant and every appliance needs to be in sync. If supply and demand fall out of balance, even for seconds, the frequency drifts. And if it drifts too far, the way that the grid protects itself is through what we call blackouts. So it's very severe whenever something like that happens. And this is actually my long way of talking about AR data centers in particular because
I think the complexity of that from a power grid perspective is that if I can use the analogy of a stadium, so picture a stadium with 70,000 people and then a person here is a GPU. So everyone is talking, eating, walking around at random and all of that randomness you can think about this like it all blends into a steady hum. That's a normal data center.
But then you have an AI data center. So that's not just 70,000 people doing their own thing independent of each other. It's 70,000 people who watch the same game. So everyone cheers at the same time whenever there's a goal. And it's not a steady hum. It's cheering and then back to a steady hum. And the grit isn't built for that. Remember what we talked about before about, you know, you're predicting, yes, we're coming back from work and then we go to sleep and like
it's a very, very gradual decline. That is not the way the power grids have to work today, but that's the way that they're being built. And you can't just build a new power grid. That's not really how it works. In theory, yes, in practicality, it's very, very complicated, very expensive, and all kinds of issues. We probably shouldn't go into it today here. But what is amazing about these CETL batteries is that they sit between the data center and the grid and it absorbs those thoughts. And an AR data center is, you could say it's even worse than a football stadium because
you might get a few goals throughout those 90 minutes. But then whenever you train a model, it will take you weeks to train a model. And then you have this cheering and then steady hum. And it happens every second or two. So it's incredible tiresome for the grid to work with. And so of course, the manager, everything I just said, I guess just proves that someone is going to sell a lot of batteries. It doesn't prove that it's going to be CTL. necessarily it's going to be the winner. The storage market is growing faster than CTL's storage shipments. So
competitors are taking their share right now. But why and sort of like very much putting the spotlight on you here, why does CETL win the market and not just participate in it? First of all, stake. That's a very interesting way to explain the badly used case for in AI data center, especially with the World Cup just concluding. Well, with regards to your point about storage market growing faster than CETL's storage shipment, that is true.
Even though CATL is the number one player in energy storage space and the segment grew installations by roughly 30% last year, but that was below the overall industry growth rate of close to about 80% if I'm not wrong. I believe one key reason why this segment did not grow at a faster rate for CATL last year was because of capacity constraints. So CATL's utilization rate
Last year was around 97%, meaning that they sold pretty much what they could produce. Now this year some of those constraints should ease up as new manufacturing capacity comes online. So it will be important to see if CATL can start regaining market share in this segment. In fact, if you look at the latest quarterly result CATL's energy storage sales for the first half of 2026,
grew by about 88% year on year. And the storage volume nearly doubled year on year. So this gives some data point around the CATL's potential market share position in the energy storage space. Thank you for paying some call around that, Manish. The other thing I want to talk about is battery releasing. And I'll admit that whenever I first read about this, it sounded a bit strange to me.
at least in Europe and North America, this is somewhat novel idea. In China, it's already happening at scale. And so the concept is simple, actually very, very smart, I should say. You buy the car, but not the battery. And you subscribe to the battery. And I can mention like the first time I was like, what? You're you're you don't buy a battery. But anyways, I started to think about it in a different way. And I was thinking, OK, so this is sort of like whenever you have a phone plan and you don't pay the
$2,000 upfront for the phone, you pay monthly. And then whenever the phone gets old, you swap it for a new one. And whenever I thought about it like that, I was like, oh, okay, that makes sense. And so it's the same idea, except the batteries is roughly a third of the price of electric car. Historically, it's even more so removing it lowers the sticker price significantly and allows for more people to enter the market. And then there's swapping. So instead of
I'm going to say charge for an hour. I think you already mentioned that it's actually today. You do it much, much faster. But anyways, you drive to a station and then very short period of time, you have a machine that changes the battery. Now, I should say to be clear, most Chinese drivers are still charging at home. But for someone driving to the grocery store, swapping is nice to have, I guess, but certainly not a need to have. But
I've learned that there are already several thousand swap stations across the country. And of course, then you have taxis and trucks where the vehicle earns money, you know, every hour it moves. So, swapping becomes perhaps more the default. I don't know. But for those drivers, you know, time is money. And so, time at a charter is therefore also lost income. And I guess what I found interesting as an investor is how this
could potentially change CETL's business model. The stop being accompanied and sells your battery once and instead the battery stays in the pool at CETL and his partners own and operate and they never lose the battery. It comes back, it gets checked, get reused and eventually recycled. And so CETL owns the whole lifetime of the asset. And so, you as a user, which is very, very nice, you don't have to worry about the battery getting old.
And I think you're going back to this example here with someone with an iPhone, for example, we all know the feeling like we bought this expensive gadget or but also a gadget can be without them after a few years, you're like, oh my God, like it's just like the batteries just terrible, right? And so Apple needs new money, we need to buy a new one, whatnot. And with an EV, the same problem knocks thousands of dollars off the car's value. But then under this model, that's not
Their problem is not the consumer's problem anymore. And of course, capitalism is brutal. We always talk about that here on the show, but the batteries are heavy, stations are expensive, the automakers have to agree on standards. So I'm not saying by any means that better releasing is just a free lunch, but manage your the ball. So how big could this become? Yeah, so battery swapping is popular in China and CATL has close to 2000 stations and growing.
The company builds modular battery packs that are co-developed with major Chinese automakers. So it basically locks in the customers. And the cost of setting up the network is shared with various partners. So it is not CATL alone taking the entire cost upfront. The advantages of battery swapping, as you mentioned, are cost and time. So the average swap time is less than 100 seconds.
so taxis and heavy commercial vehicles can be on the road for longer with low downtime. The risk here is that with the battery charging time coming down, the time advantage might not be that significant, especially for smaller vehicles. But what CTA is also doing is that they are adding superchargers to these swapping stations. So the same station can cater to both battery swapping as well as fixed battery vehicles.
And I think this is where the scale of CATL, both in battery packs and charging network can help them to provide a faster payoff for these stations. Thank you, Manish, for that caller. You know, one thing I realized as I was diving deeper into CATL was that they're not just making different types of batteries. To your point before this episode, you know, it takes stakes in other companies and so far, more than 150.
Now, one of them is deep seek. And this might be my like one, the staying of the Chinese market board. Whenever I looked at all their investments, that was the one that sort of like stood out to me. And perhaps many of our listeners would know that name, you know, it's China's AI darling, if you wonder, this is the lab that took everyone in Silicon Valley here in early 2025. You know, they're building this frontier model on the cheap. And in June, they took outside money for the first time. So it was roughly 7 billion.
at a valuation above 50 billion USD. CETL itself put in 700 million. And I should say for the record that these numbers come from press reports. These are all private deals, similar to whenever you have between say Microsoft and OpenAI. There are certain reports, but it's not like an official document. You can just go in and see these all the terms. So anyways, the rationale is straightforward. AR centers that we already established, they're power hungry. CETL are investing in the future customer.
And this is to the point before not just a Chinese phenomenon. You have NVIDIA committed more than $40 billion to equity stakes in 2026. And of course, I can't help but myself as scrutinize like how that carousel works, whether taking different stakes in each other's that seems to be some kind of voucher thing. Anyways, I don't want to digress. But it is kind of interesting how this ecosystem is built around the biggest tech companies, not just
in the US, but also in China. But they also do it differently. If you look at the biggest tech companies compare the strategic stakes to the market caps, actually, Chinese companies hold roughly 10% of their market cap, whereas Americans, it's only 4%. Now, in China, they've been doing it for the better part of 15 years. The stakes are also brought to supply chains, you're looking at mines, customers, as we saw there with deep-seek political alignment.
American big tech companies, at least for now, looks a little lighter. It could change. This certainly went heavily in for the past 18 months and all of it was in is specifically in AI. And of course, then you have a lot of this on paper prices, meaning whatever the latest funding round would tell it to be. So that gives you some kind of distorted numbers, but still gives you a way to perhaps be directionally correct.
Man, you talked to us about TATL trading at around 18 times operating profit. How do you treat these 150 plus stakes? Did you give them any value and should investor CCATL as a battery maker with a side portfolio or is the portfolio even a part of the mode? Yeah. I think the TATL's investment portfolio I think is more strategic than financial. It helps them to achieve vertical integration.
It spans upstream mining companies to downstream automakers and power infrastructure player in the energy storage system. Their investment in DeepSeq, I believe, is part of their AI data center integration play. Although I think investing in a foundational AI model lab is going to the extreme end of vertical integration. In terms of valuation, it is tricky to value these investments because
most of them are private and depending on their stake, they are treated differently in the financial accounting point of view. I believe the simplest way to look at it is to see the long-term equity investment line item on their balance sheet. So, as of last quarter, this number was about $11 billion, so slightly less than one time operating profit. So, when we look at 18 times operating profit, I did not account for the value of these long-term investments.
But if you include them at book value, then it drops to about 17 times. But I would categorize these numbers, these investments are more as a competitive advantage play through vertical integration and less as a financial investment play. All right, Manish and Ralph, this was what we had planned here for the bull bear thesis here. I wanted to ask you here before we transition into the final segment.
You both presented your case, but do you have any concluding remarks? I don't know. Have you become more various after speaking with Ralph or perhaps even converted Ralph? I don't know. Yeah, it will be interesting to hear from Ralph, what does he think? I think it's always interesting to hear the other side of the argument. As Charlie Munger has said that you have to argue the other side better than the other player. So I think understanding the bare thesis is extremely important and seeing whether
you are missing anything. It is a capitalism is brutal. So it's always a learning game. And this was a fantastic episode. I really enjoyed it. And would love to hear what all things about this business. It was extremely enlightening to me when the show, like I said at the beginning, cattle, CATL, I didn't know which way to go there, but I do now.
I've learned so much about batteries that I didn't know and it is, I think is, is stick pointed out that industry has changed and so much has changed and what we've learned and where we're going. It's the same way that my education started coming about when I got thrust into a data center and learning about data centers. So it's truly amazing and
I believe it's like so many of the people I hear talking about AI. I heard Sam Allman yesterday in a podcast saying, the world has changed. It is totally different. And then I heard a scientist speaking about a week ago and saying that this is the greatest time in the world to be alive, that so many things are happening. And I'm in complete accord with that.
and getting into something like C.A.T.L. and speaking about this and learning about it just really excites me. I'm like Stig. It's so many things have changed and we are in the right in the middle of the change and I just want to say to you Manish thank you for bringing those to us and giving us such a great education about it and I really dug deep to try to get a better case going here.
to say these things. Thank you, Rafa. Thank you so much. Yeah, I have to say I really enjoy this bull bear format. And I should say that one of the reasons why we decided to go this route is, and perhaps it's our own biases, I don't know, but very often whenever you are bullish about a company, you end up speaking with other people who are also bullish. And so you sort of like end up in the same acre chamber and you pat each other on the back and everyone agrees that
We all so smart because we are invested in the same company. And so having someone who is the bear, but also, you know, has the permission to kind of, I wouldn't say rude, but you're sort of something like if people are excited about a stock, you didn't really don't want to be the guy who's like, well, you're probably all wrong. You know, it's like that guy doesn't get invited back, right? So like giving someone in this case, Ralph the permission to be the
the bear and you ask the critical questions and you know I think that's just so it's so incredible important so so thank you Ralph for playing along and I don't know if you want to play bowl next time or if it's more fun to be the bear but just want to say thank you for providing such a compelling bear case. Well I appreciate that and I would say that for the audience listening did you know you think of a CPA that I am.
and a career that I've spent as being a CPA and the work that I've done there as being no, I was always saying no, but I look forward to being the bull. Fantastic. All right. So before we let the listeners go, I just wanted to say that if anyone are interested in hearing more from Ralph, he'll be speaking at the TIP intrinsic value conference in New York City. That is on September 19th. And Ralph, what will you be speaking about?
Well, of course, I am going to be speaking about investments, but more importantly, I'll be sharing the story of how investing actually became my third career. My first career, as I mentioned, is a traditional CPA. I prepared financial statements, audited financial statements, tax returns, consulting.
And then that led into my second career as a forensic accountant. And that's where I investigated all these financial shenanigans, partners cooking the books, massive Ponzi schemes like we all heard about Bernie Madoff and multi-billion dollar bank frauds. And so if you name the fraud, I probably investigated it.
But people often ask me if tracking down the frauds uniquely prepared me for a career in investments. And I honestly have to tell them no. It was a helpful foundation, certainly. But it wasn't until I found a community of lifelong learners, like the ones right here in TIP, that I truly learned how to dig into the fundamental analysis of a business.
I met people like Manish who really gets in there and digs into the economic moats and figures out what makes a business genuinely investable. And that's just really exciting. So blending my past careers with the new one, it's been an incredible education for me in learning how to invest. And the people I've met along the journey have been come forever friends.
That evolution and the frameworks I picked up along the way. That's exactly what I'm going to be sharing in New York. That's fantastic. Thank you, Ralph. We'll make sure to link to the conference in the show note. We also have a bunch of other cool stuff. We have a dinner with William Green and a bunch of other activities there. So you can read more about it on the website. I wanted to give the audience the opportunity to connect with you. How can they do that?
Well, I still have a LinkedIn page. I think it's linked to my firm, which I formally retired a year ago, but it's still linked there. So I have a LinkedIn page. And you can also email me. My email address is Ralph.Somervr.com. Fantastic. Thank you, Ralph. I also wanted to mention that
Not only do we have the event in New York City, we also have an event in Q1. We're still finalizing on the exact date, but it will be sometime in Q1 in Singapore, exclusive for the Mastermind members. And Manish is going to be hosting that on behalf of TIP. And again, we'll be talking a ton more about that in the next quarter's episode between the three of us. But Manish, where can the audience engage with you?
Thanks, take this was wonderful and I look forward to the Singapore event with the mastermind members and those who want to connect with me you can find me on LinkedIn. My profile ID is Manish Haifan Karira and yeah, I look forward to connecting with you. Thank you Manish and thank you Jens. I look forward to inviting you back here for next quarters episode and yeah, like we talked about perhaps we should turn the tables perhaps Manish you're going to be very next time and
Ralph, you're going to find an amazing company to be bullish. Yeah, CPAs are not always negative. Fantastic. Yeah, great. I look forward to being, to taking the other opposite side of the argument. Thanks for listening to TIP. Follow the Investors Podcast on your favorite podcast app and visit theinvestorspodcast.com for show notes and educational resources.
This podcast is for informational and entertainment purposes only and does not provide financial, investment, tax or legal advice. The content is impersonal and does not consider your objectives, financial situation or needs. Investing involves risk including possible loss of principal and past performance is not a guarantee of future results. Listeners should do their own research and consult a qualified professional before making any financial decisions. Nothing on this show is a recommendation or solicitation to buy or sell any security or other financial product. Hosts, guests,
and the Investors' Podcast Network may hold positions in securities discussed and may change those positions at any time without notice. References to any third-party products, services, or advertisers do not constitute endorsements and the Investors' Podcast Network is not responsible for any claims made by them. Copyright by the Investors' Podcast Network. All rights reserved.